GAURANG SINGH

PROJECT MANAGER @

EMAIL: gaurang0705@gmail.com **PHONE:** 9599343931 **LOCATION:** Ranchi , India **LINKEDIN:** linkedin.com/in/gaurang0705 **GITHUB:** github.com/gaurang0705

SUMMARY

An Data science enthusiast and presently pursuing 9- month certification from Springboard. Working as Project Manager for Pan IIT Reach for India Foundation for past two years with proven experience in team management, procurement, government liasioning and budget analysis. Has worked in IT sector for 3 year for IBM India Pvt. Ltd. fas an SAP MM consultant and been part of end to end SAP implementation team.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology, BHU (VARANASI)

June 2009 - May 2013

Springboard Data Science Career Track,

June 2020 - Current

Certification 2020 9-month intensive course in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL.

EMPLOYMENT

Pan IIT Alumni Reach for India, Foundation, Project Manager & Procurement, Ranchi

Nov. 2018 - Current

IBM India Pvt Ltd., SAP MM consultant, Ranchi

June 2013 - June 2016

SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE: Python, SQL, Data Visualization, Data Wrangling, Statistical Modeling, Machine Learning, Predictive Modeling, Clustering & Regression, Image Processing, Decision Tree, Hadoop, Spark ERP - SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGEMENT: SAP MM, SAP SD, Master Data Management, Data Migration, HQPC

MANAGEMENT: Vendor Management, RFQ Preparation, Team Management, Supply chain and logistics, Contract Negotiation

PROJECTS

Capstone Project: Demand Prediction_ Predictive Modelling

Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Demand Prediction for market capitalization for a given Beverage company.

Data wrangling for cleaning and reformation of the data.

Data Visualization for market as well as product insights .

Data preprocessing for standardization and PCA for feature selection.

Predictive Modelling using Linear regression, Random Forest and XGBOOST.

ICMR COVID-19 BSL-3 Lab Implementation

May 2020 - Dec. 2020

Design and Implementation of BSL -3 Labs in Medical Colleges of Jharkhand Government .

Requirement gathering and data scaling for the project realization.

Procurement and process integration for Lab Set up.

Total Project Cost - 5 cr.

Skill Development Center - Set Up

Mar. 2019 - Current

Part of team responsible for proposal, designing and setting up of 44 skill development centers across Jharkhand. Budget Preparation and Procurement worth 20 cr. for 44 skill development centers i.e. 35 Gurukuls (Short term Vocational Courses) and 9 Kaushal College (Long term Vocational Courses).

Responsible for setting up of Nursing Kaushal College, Sahibganj and Itki which are located in Aspirational Districts for upliftment of underprivileged section through vocational skill training and development.

Total project cost: 10 cr.

Amerisource Bergen Corporation Acquisition Roll Out - IBM

Oct. 2013 - June 2016

ABC is an American distribution company and was part of SAP roll out project for the newly acquired companies .

End to End implementation of on-boarding the older Legacy system to SAP.

Lead a team of 4 for successful implementation of SAP Enhancement project to map business requirement in SAP.

Report analysis and insights sharing with client for process optimization.

Master Data migration .

Root Cause analysis .

Requirement Gathering and Function document preparation.

SLA monitoring and reporting .

IBM Fast Track Implementation project

July 2013 - Sept. 2013

End to End implementation of SAP business process including configuration and master data management.

AWARDS

IBM Service Excellence Award, IBM India Pvt Ltd

Mar. 2014

Awarded for Service Delivery .

Client Appreciation Award, Amerisource Bergen Cooporation

Aug. 2015